Good evening ladies and gentlemen. A
very warm welcome to ICICI Lombard
Gender Insurance Company Limited Q3 and
9 months FY2026 earnings conference call
from the senior management. We have with
us today Mr. Sanjie Mantri MD and CEO of
the company. Mr. Gopal Balachandran CFO
Mr. Mr. Anand Singhi, Chief Retail and
Government. Mr. Girish Nayak, Chief
Technology and Health Underwriting and
Claims. Mr. Sep Goradia, Chief Corporate
Solutions International and Bank
assurance. And Mr. Goro Vora, Chief
Reinsurance, Underwriting and Claims for
Property and Casualty.
Please note that any statements,
comments are made in today's call that
may look like forward-looking statements
are based on the information presently
available to the management and do not
constitute an indication of any future
performance as future involved risks and
uncertaintities which could cause
results to differ materially from the
current views being expressed. As a
reminder, all participant lines will be
in the listenonly mode and there will be
an opportunity for you to ask questions
after the presentation concludes. Should
you need assistance during the
conference call, please signal an
operator by pressing star and then zero
on your touchstone phone.
I now hand the conference over to Mr.
Sanjie Mantri, MD and CEO ICIC Lombard
General Insurance Limited. Thank you and
over to you sir.
Good evening to each one of you. Thank
you for joining the earnings conference
call for ICL Lombard for quarter 3 and 9
months financial year 2026.
At the outset, let me wish you all a
very happy new year and best of health
and happiness.
I would like to give you a brief
overview of the recent economic and
industry trends which has shaped the
operating environment over the past few
months. Following that, our CFO Mr. The
Gopal Balach Chandran will take you
through the company's financial
performance for the recently concluded
quarter and 9 months. The Indian economy
recorded a GDP growth of 8.2% in quarter
2 up from 7.8 in the preceding quarter.
The expansion was underpinned by
sustained government capital expenditure
coupled with an increase in private
capex rup service activi services
activity and a rebound in private
consumption. Consumption was further
supported by easing inflation and the
GST rationalization implemented in late
September 2025.
Coming to Q3 financial year 2026, the
index of industrial production, IIP data
indicates positivity supported by
manufacturing growth, continued
infrastructure development and a
turnaround in consumer good segment. EV
bill generation and toll collections
during the same period recorded growth
of 13% and 17% YI reflecting strong
underlying economic activity. We believe
that these high frequency indicators
should augur well for a commercial and
of segmented
by GST rationalization the automo sector
has seen a significant uptick in sales.
According to retail sales data based on
WAN registration, the auto industry
recorded a growth of 19.5% for quarter
3, 2026, resulting in a total of 9.4
million vehicles sold.
Within this, private car had seen a
growth of 19.3% translating to 1.3
million vehicles. The two-heer segment
grew by 19.2%
with the 7 million vehicles whereas
commercial vehicles grew by 22.2%.
with 1.1 million vehicle being sold.
Interestingly, the overall growth in the
vehicle sales is the highest in last 12
quarters. To add to it, this growth is
more broad-based as tier three cities
and beyond have demonstrated faster
growth in both private car and two-heer
segments. This is also coraborated by
strong growth of 28.8% in tractor sales
for the quarter. Overall, the
acceleration in new vehicle sales for
the quarter has also led to a 7.7%
growth for calendar year 2025 with a
28.1 million units being sold.
The landmark decision of exemption of
GST on retail health insurance has
significantly improved affordability and
increased awareness.
The industry has passed on the complete
benefit of GST exemptions to the end
consumers.
This has led to an increase in policy
uptake as more customers are seeing
health seeking healthcare protection.
Here too the growth in retail health
appears to be broad-based across markets
and it's supported by a surge in
firsttime buyers especially for tier 2
and tier three cities which is a
positive for this sector.
On the regulatory front, the government
of India took a significant step during
the quarter by introducing
forward-looking reforms in the insurance
laws with the passage of Sapka Bimma
Saki Raka amendment of insurance laws
bill 2025.
While most of these amendments will have
farreaching effects on the insurance
sector over time, a few important
changes pertaining to the insurance act
are as follows. Foreign investment in an
Indian insurance company has enhanced
from 74% to 100% thereby supporting
capital inflows enabling provisions in
the amendment act to facilitate business
other than traditional insurance
underwriting and distribution thereby
allowing insurers to offer holistic risk
management services.
Simplification of provisions relating to
investments of assets.
We are excited about these changes and
we do believe that this should be
structurally positive and would
accelerate the growth and development of
the insurance sector. This will also
facilitate ease of doing business and
provide better protection and risk
management solutions to the policy
holders.
In another significant reform in
November 2025, the government of India
formally made effective four new central
labor codes including the code on social
security 2020. Consequent to this,
benefits like gratuitity, leave and cash
etc paid on basic salary are now
required to be paid basis the new
broader definition of wage.
We believe this changes should translate
into a more resilient workforce and
strengthen employee security over time.
This change has a one-time impact on the
financials which will be covered by
Gopal in his section.
Let me now dwell upon the industry
performance for the period ended 31st
December 2025.
The general insurance industry reported
a GDPI growth of 8.7% for 9 month 2026
excluding crop and mass cell segment.
The GDPI growth at 13.3 growth stood at
13.3% for the period 9 month 2026.
Speaking on specific segments within the
industry, commercial segment recorded a
healthy growth of 14.8 8% for 9 month
2026 and 16.3% for quarter 3 2026.
This growth led by strong momentum in
the fire line which grew at 20.1% for 9
month 2026.
As mentioned above, this is driven by an
increase in capex particularly in areas
such as roads, railways and renewable
energy.
The motor segment grew at 8.9% in 9
months 2026.
compared to 7.6% in H1 2026.
For quarter 3 financial year 2026, the
growth stood at 10.9% supported by
festive season demand and the positive
impact of GST rationalization. Health
segment grew at 14.2%
for 9 months 2026 with a strong momentum
of 27.6% 6% growth in quarter 3 of 2026
led by retail health which grew at 33.6%
and group health growth of 23.1%
underscoring strong demand across the
segment.
On the other hand, industry combined
ratio worsened from 113.3%
in H1 of 2025 to 119.2% 2% in H1 of 2026
indicating continued underwriting
pressure. During the same period, ICL
core moved from 103.2%
in financial year 2025 to 104.0%
in H1 of 2026, reinforcing a superior
financial performance through discipline
underwriting.
The motor line of business remains a key
area of stress with the industry core
increasing from 124.8% 8% in H1 of 2025
to 128.5%
in H1 of 2026.
IC alumba demonstrated better portfolio
management in motor insurance with the
combined ratio improving from 108 to
106.9%
during the same period.
I will now proceed to present our
company's performance across key
business segments.
For 9 month 2026, gross domestic premium
income of the company grew by 3.6%
compared to industry growth of 8.7% for
the same period.
Within this for quarter 3 2026 the
company reported a premium growth of
13.3%
compared to industry growth of 11.5%
thereby improving its market share from
8.1% for quarter 3 2025 to 8.3% for
quarter 3 2026
for December 2025 in particular the
company's growth in GDPI was 16.1% in
comparison to the industry growth of
14.4%.
Excluding cross crop and mass health the
company recorded a growth of 7.5%
during 9 month financial year 2026
against the industry growth of 13.3%
within this for quarter 3 2025 the
company record a growth of 16.4%
as against the industry growth of 20.1%.
In the commercial line segment our
growth stood at 7.4% 4% and 6.8% for
quarter 3 2026 and 9 month 2026
respectively. While the industry grew by
16.3% for quarter 3 2026 and 14.8% for 9
month 2026.
We continue to be focused on delivering
profitable growth through discipline
underwriting, food and risk selection
and portfolio diversification resulting
in the growth of fire segment by 18.8%
8% in quarter 3 2026 driven by 27.4%
growth inc segment.
Further the company delivered a 19.3%
growth in fire compared to 15.8 industry
growth for the month of December 2025.
In the engineering segment, our growth
stood at 15.2% and 13.3% for quarter 3
2026 and 9 month 2026 respectively.
While the industry during the same
period grew by 11.5%
and 12.9% respectively. This led to we
attaining leadership position position
in engineering segment for the 9 month
2026.
On the other side for 9 month 2026 the
company's growth for marine cargo and
liability segment was not in line with
the industry growth on on account of
portfolio rationalization. However, we
continue to maintain our leadership
position in these lines.
In motor segment for 9 months 2026, the
company record a growth of 5% whereas
the industry grew by 8.9%.
While I while our growth in H1 of 2026
was only 2.2%, a rebound was observed in
Q3 2026 driven by an underlying buoyancy
in new motor vehicle sales.
Consequently, the motor segment grew by
9.3% in Q3 2026, supported by a strong
growth of 16.1% in December 2025.
Despite heightened competitive intensity
in the recent quarters, we remain
focused on profitable growth driven by
continuous expansion across distribution
channels and a more granular portfolio
segmentation. Importantly, the company
continues to maintain it leadership
position in the motor segment with a
market share of 10.7% for 9 months 2026.
The company's portfolio motor portfolio
mix of private car, two-heer and
commercial vehicle stood at 53.6,
25.8%
and 20.6% respectively for 9 month
financial year 2026.
In the health segment, the company grew
by 42% and a 13.8% for quarter 3 2026
and for 9 month 2026 respectively as
against the industry growth of 27.6% and
14.2% for quarter 3 financial year 2026
and 9 month 2026 respectively.
Our health business delivered a robust
growth of 85.8% 8% in quarter 3 2026 and
44.8%
in 9 month 2026 significantly
outperforming the industry growth of
33.6%
in quarter 3 and 16.5% for 9 month 2026.
Our growth was fueled by new to industry
customer growth of 1.7x for quarter 3
2026 and 1.4 four times for 9 month
2026.
Thus, our market share increases to 4%
in 9 month 2026 compared to 3.2% for the
same period in the previous year. And
for quarter 3, 2026, our market share
has increased to 4.5%
from 3.2% for the same period in
previous year. The strong performance
has also been driven by sustained
investment in strengthening our retail
distribution capabilities across
channels.
The group health segment registered a
growth of 26.6%
and 5.9% for quarter 3 2026 and 9 month
2026 respectively. While the industry
grew by 23.1% for quarter 3 2026 and
12.6% for 9 month 2026.
I would now like to apprise you of
certain strategic initiatives that
continue to drive operational excellence
and customer sensit centricity across
the organization.
The one hour one call center initiative
continues to deliver strong momentum in
the company's transition towards a
digital first doityourselfvicing
model. In December over 60% of the total
service engagements were managed
digitally as against 38% only for April
2025. This was possible due to our AI AI
interventions through various BS which
has helped customers adopting DIY
service modes.
This has led to improved turnaround
times, service consistency and increased
productivity. Our differentiated service
desk initiatives which we can which we
had spoken about in a previous call have
resulted in increase of our call center
NPS to 73 in Q3 of 2026 from 60 in Q1 of
financial year 2026.
Building on a one digital framework we
continue to take positive strides toward
offering a seamless and omni channel
experience across our website and the
take care platform. As you might recall,
the INKare app was initially launched to
provide a continuum of care for our
health insurance customers. Over time,
the app has continuously evolved with
new functionaries and features, making
it a comprehensive one-stop solution for
service and sales across multiple retail
product lines.
The app has now crossed 19.7 million
downloads as of December 31st, 2025,
reflective growing customer engagement
and dig digital adoption.
The customer registered the the company
registered a GWP of 3.54 billion for 9
month 2026 from the ILCare app as
against 1.45 billion for the same period
last year.
Take care has also made significant
progress in addressing key customer
service requirements and delivering a
seamless insurance experience. Just to
highlight for Trip Secure Plus, our
premier travel insurance product,
customers can now independently manage
claims, policy cancellations, extensions
and modifications through the app. These
enhancements have enabled 93%
of services service requests to be
processed on DIY basis without the need
for manual intervention
leading to a corresponding reduction in
support call volumes. Notably 79% of
claim intimation for Trip Secure Plus in
December 2025 were also initiated
through Takeare app as compared to 22%
in July 2025.
In order to continually enhance our
efficiency levels in motor claims, we
have expanded our cashless garage
network from 13,600 plus garages in
quarter 3 2025 to 15,000 garages in
quarter 3 2026.
75.2%
of our nonm claims for quarter 3 2026
were serviced at PPN, up from 73.6 in
quarter 3, 2025, leading to a enhanced
customer experience.
In the retail segment, 99.6% of our
total claims were paid within 30 days.
And for motor insurance own damage
segment, 96.8% of our claims were paid
within 30 days for the period ended 9
month 2026. As a result, our NPS for H1
2026 for health claims stood at 70 and
for motor claims stood at 69,
reinforcing our position as a
customercentric organization.
In conclusion, the domestic macro
environment remains supportive with
broad-based consumption showing healthy
momentum. We remain focused on building
a sustainable long-term franchise
anchored in the strength of our
technology processes and service
architecture. Through our one team
initiative, we continue to sharpen
execution, drive consistency, and
deliver customer outcomes at scale. We
are well positioned to convert a more
supportive demand environment into a
steady highquality growth while
maintaining discipline in underwriting,
service delivery and operating
efficiency. I will now request Gopal to
take you through the financial numbers
for the period 9 month 2026. Uh thanks
Ajiv and uh good evening to each one of
you. I will now give you a brief
overview of the financial performance of
the recently concluded quarter and 9
months. We have uploaded the results
presentation on our website. You all can
access it as we walk you through the
performance numbers. Uh with effect from
October 1, 2024, long-term products are
accounted on a 1 byN basis as mandated
by a regulator. Please refer to the
investor presentation on slide 16 for a
much more detailed information on
comparison of financials on N and 1 by N
basis. Uh now let me update on GDPI
numbers. Please note these numbers are
on 1 byN basis. The GDP of the company
was at uh 213.72 billion rupees in 9
months current year as against rupees
206.23 billion in 9 months FI25 a growth
of 3.6% as against the industry growth
of 8.7%.
GDP of the company was at 70 billion
70.41 41 billion in Q3 FI26 as against
rup 62.14 billion in Q3 FI25 a growth of
13.3% as against the industry growth of
11.5%.
Resulting in our market share to grow
from 8.1% in quarter 3 last year to 8.3%
in quarter 3 of the current year. On the
retail side of the business, GDP of the
motor segment was at rupes 33.99 billion
in Q3 FI26 as against rupes 31.09 09
billion in Q3 FI25 registering a growth
of 9.3%.
The advanced premium for motor segment
was at 41.26 billion rupees as at
December 31 2025 as against rupees 39.13
billion as at September 30 2025. GDP of
the health segment was at rupes 20.44 in
Q3 this year as against rupes 14.53
billion in Q3 FI25
registering a growth of 40.6%.
Within this our retail health segment
registered a robust growth of 85.8%.
During the same period GDP of our
commercial line was at rupes 15.72
billion in Q3 FI26 as against rupees
14.63 billion in Q3 FI25
registering a growth of 7.4%. Our agents
which includes the point of sale
distribution count was 1 lak 50,458
as at December 31 2025 up from 14748
as at September 30 2025. Our combined
ratio on 1 by n basis was 104.2%
in 9 months current year as against
102.9%
in 9 months last year. On an N basis,
our combined ratio was 103.1% in the
current year as against 102.8% in 9
months last year.
The combined ratio on again 1 by N for
this quarter 3 current year was 104.5%.
as against 102.7%
in Q3 last year again on an N basis for
this year quarter 3 combined ratio was
103.1
as against 102.3 in Q3 FI25
we have been talking about the impact of
CAT losses so if one was to exclude the
impact of CAT losses of rupes84 billion
in 9 months current year and 94 billion
in 9 months of last year the combined
ratio on a 1 byN basis was 103 3.7% and
102.3% respectively. The same numbers on
an N basis was 102.6% and 102.2%
respectively.
Uh now coming to the quarter excluding
the impact of CAT losses of rupees.11
billion in Q3 current year. The combined
ratio on 1 by N was 104.3
and the same numbers on an N basis was
103%.
There were no CAT losses in Q3 FI25 and
as mentioned by Sanji in his opening
remarks excluding the impact of wage
code of rupees.55
billion our combined ratio on a 1 byN
basis for 9 months current year and
quarter 3 current year was 103.9%
and 103.5%
respectively.
On a n basis our combined ratio
excluding the wage code wage code impact
was 102.8. 8% and 102.2% for 9 months
and Q3 respectively. Our investment
assets during the quarter rose to rupes
582.96 billion as at December 31, 2025
up from rupes 562 billion as at
September 30, 2025. Our investment
leverage net of borrowings was 3.6 times
at December 31, 2025 at against 3.57 at
September 30, 2025.
Investment income was at rupes 37.57
billion in 9 months current year as
against rupes 33.73 billion in 9 months
last year. On a quarterly basis,
investment income was at rupees 12.19
billion in Q3 current year as against
rupes 11.21 billion in Q3 last year. Our
capital gains net of environmental
investment assets stood at rupes 9.33
billion in 9 months current year as
against rupees 7.96 billion in 9 months
last year. Capital gains stood at rupes
3.17 billion in quarter 3 current year
as compared to rups 2.76 billion in Q3
last year. On a 1 byN basis, our PBT
grew by 10.8% at rupees 29.41 billion in
9 months current year as against rupees
26.53 billion in 9 months last year on
an again for the quarter on a 1 by basis
PBT grew by 9.4%
for the current quarter as against rupes
9.6 6 billion in Q3 last year.
Consequently, on a 1 byN basis, PAT grew
by 11.3%
at rupees 22.225 billion in 9 months
current year as against rupes 19.99
billion in 9M last year. The same
numbers on an end basis for profit after
tax grew by 13.8% at rupees 22.22
billion in 9 months current year as
against rupes 19.53 billion in 9 months
last year. On a one by basis, fat
degrouped by 9.1% at 6.59 billion in Q3
current year from 7.24 billion in Q3
last year. Again coming back to N basis,
Pratt remained flattish at 6.8 billion
in Q3 current year from 6.79 billion in
Q3 last last year. Excluding the impact
of wage code uh on a 1 byN basis PA was
rupes 22.67 67 billion in 9 months
current year and rupes 7 billion in Q3
current year registering a growth of
13.4% and a degrowth of 3.3%
respectively. The same numbers on an end
basis PAT was rupees 22.64 billion for 9
months current year and rupees 7.21
billion in Q3 of this quarter
registering a growth of 15.9% and 6.3%
respectively.
Coming to ROE on a 1 byN basis it was
19.5% in 9 months as against 20.8% in 9
months last year. ROE for the quarter 3
current year was 16.5% as against 21.5%
in Q3 FI25 excluding the wage code
impact on a 1 byN basis ROE was 19.8%
and 17.5% in 9 months and Q3 of the
current year respectively. Solveny ratio
was at 2.69 69 times at December 31,
2025 as against 2.73 times at September
30, 2025 continues to be higher than the
minimum regulatory requirement of 1.5
times. As I conclude, I would like to
state that uh we are all aligned with
our ethos of driving profitable growth,
consistent and sustainable value
creation for all our stakeholders while
ensuring that the interest of the policy
holders are in the forefront at all
times. I'd like to thank you all for
attending this earnings call and we will
now be happy to take any questions that
you have. Thank you.
>> Thank you very much. We will now begin
with the question and answer session.
Anyone who wishes to ask a question may
press star and then one on their
touchstone phone.
If you wish to remove yourself from the
question queue, you may press star and
two. Participants are requested to use
handsets while asking a question.
Ladies and gentlemen, we will wait for a
moment while the question Q assembles.
>> Our first question comes from the line
of Supraatim Duta from Jeff. Please go
ahead.
>> Hi. Um thanks for the opportunity. My
first question is on the labor codes. Um
you know we understand that you know
there is a 50 crore impact from you know
the labor code changes. Just wanted to
understand what proportion of this was
recurring versus what proportion of this
was one time. You know that was the
first question. Secondly, you know,
coming to growth now, you know, despite
the GST tailwinds, um, you know, the
growth even on the motor side, if I see
has been, you know, slower than what the
industry has, uh, witnessed and I do
understand that, you know, competition
has been elevated. But you know the
regulator at the regulatory level has
taken multiple steps you know be it
expense of management guidelines or you
know discussions with industry you know
to reduce the competitive intensity or
bring in some bit of rationality yet we
are you know not able to see that happen
so from here you know if I'm taking a
two to three years view what will you
know drive growth in the motor segment
for a player like you which already has
10 11% market share you know that that's
you know if you could throw some light
on that you know that would be very
helpful. And lastly on the motor TP loss
ratio uh I do understand last time there
was a TP release.
Uh but uh you know this time it seems to
be a more normalized loss ratio. Um
could we assume that you know the
reserve release is hold and you know
there is no further release that that
would come in the fourth quarter or you
know could there be further releases
that would come in the fourth quarter.
You know if you could throw some light
on the reserve release but that would
also be very helpful. Thank you.
Thanks. Thanks. Thanks for those
questions. Uh on the first one, uh so
far as the labor code is concerned,
obviously uh uh uh the impact of 55
crores uh in that sense is one time
because it's primarily the liability
resulting from an actual valuation uh
for the past service uh cost uh in so
far as uh uh wages is concerned. Having
said that, obviously this code is also
evolving. Uh so hence to that extent we
will have to see if there are any more
incremental guidelines or rules that are
that come into existence. But at this
point of time this is whatever has been
released thus far. This impact of 55
crores is uh what is the past service uh
cost uh which is more which is a
complete impact that we have taken in
the financials of quarter 3 and 9
months. And if you have seen also the
disclosure that we have made uh there is
an element of roughly about 17 crores.
This is the amount of unamotized cost uh
which will kind of get uh amotized over
the next three years and in line with
again the acturial report. Uh those are
the two numbers in so far as uh the
impact of wage code is concerned. 55
crores is more a one-time impact in the
financials. 17 crores of ammonized cost
is something that will get amotized over
the next uh 3 years. So that's in
response to the first one. On the
response to the third question, motor
third party loss ratios. Um I think I
will keep uh keep reiterating this. Uh
what we have told the market is um
overall motor loss ratio range that we
have spoken is between 65 to 67%.
And if you look at uh the 9month numbers
and that is something that we keep
urging that you should keep looking at
year-to- date numbers than more
quarterly outcomes. The 9month numbers
for the current year motor overall
stands at about 66.3%. This is both own
damage and third party put together. So
it's kind of pretty much playing out in
line with the range that one has spoken
about and hence to that extent uh uh we
are quite happy with the way how things
have progressed. To your point on any uh
impact of reserving etc etc. uh again we
will keep uh stressing on the fact that
there has been no change in any of our
actual assumptions and therefore to that
extent it is not that we have done
anything specific whether it was in the
context of last year or even for the
matter of fact when you look at the
numbers from a current year perspective
um so that's in response to the uh third
one and on the second one uh I will
maybe Sanjie
>> yeah I will just uh so on the motor part
uh clearly first up we are extremely
excited with the positive environment
ment that has got created as I was
giving the briefing the quarter three
numbers the growth in number of vehicles
across private car two-heer as well as
CV which was which has been more than
19% the highest in last 12 quarters is a
very very good sign uh this increase in
number has also come with the GST
rationalization which made the vehicles
cheaper and with that coming through we
had to also realign what is required and
we also spoke about in terms of how the
combine for the market has moved in
motor from 124 which was hard enough to
128. So the realignment was a very key
piece which is what we as an
organization has done. Uh consequent to
this what we are seeing is the growth of
December in particular where we have
exceeded the market expectations. We
remain very positively driven overall as
to what motor holds for us. uh we've
closed the year with a 10.7% market
share probably a loss of uh point4 or
thereabouts as to what we had 9 months
but as we close the positivity with
which we expect even Q4 numbers to build
up on the new sales would drive growth
for us because that is the combination
which we are probably best at
overall from an environment standpoints
we do see consumption playing a big role
and in that upward mobility of a
two-heer customer seeking in private car
and thereabout also is becoming very
clear also one more point which for us
is we've been a distributionled company
and the growth is broad-based which is
where they're saying that beyond P3 and
about where the market growth also is
coming it again is a big positive for us
and it will help us to drive what we
want to drive as an agenda so we are
overall on motor uh very positively
placed but the realignment in wake of
what we intensive is seen is something
which is warranted and we've always
maintained that we'll never shy away
from taking those calls but a range
mount 10.7% market where we stand we are
pretty much involved as a number one
player as a topmost player we are also
very aware of the responsibility that we
carry in the motor segment in particular
>> that's very helpful thank you
>> thank you Dr.
Thank you. Your next question comes from
the line of Sankit Koda from Aendos
Park. Please go ahead.
>> Uh yeah, thank you for the opportunity.
Uh uh you see the retail health growth
85 or 86 odd percentage in the third
quarter. Um honestly it has the
unwinding portion of last year too. So
if if I do end to end comparison uh
which which is more like to like so so
so the uh can you just uh spell out the
growth how how the retail health has
panned out uh if you look on n end to
end basis
we are not separately calling that out
so honestly uh to that extent I think
what we would say is that uh what we are
very excited is what I think Sanjiv
responded even on motor I think the
underlying demand on ground is kind of
pretty much playing out consequent to
some of the rationalizations that have
happened in the context of uh GST uh
that we have kind of talked about even
in the last quarter and and hence to
that extent uh one would say that the
growth is very very uh uh exciting and
hence to that extent while it does have
an impact uh but honestly our sense is
uh I think broadly even if I were to
kind of uh give a number even on an end
basis I think that growth would be more
or less around the same range of between
80 to 85%. So hence it doesn't kind of
change much uh which is what we had said
what we very very excited is more the
underlying definite momentum than
looking at numbers whether on an end
basis or a one by end basis
>> yeah and also you know we talking about
if you look at the numbers you've gone
on 80% plus in all three months October
November and December uh so very clearly
uh the need for differentiating that and
talking as it is it's not a easy
commentary we talking one by n by n I
for you to listen on audio itself is a
challenge. I can tell you probably you
can make more sense when you have the
script in hand. Uh but this growth and
what we have been doing over sustained
quarter also is reflected in the market
share which has increased to 4.5% in Q3.
Uh
>> which is which clearly speaks about the
underlying momentum that uh the team has
been able to build. Uh and if your
question is do you see this momentum
probably playing out even in quarter 4?
My answer would be every reason to
believe and it's dri and it's again
driven by a very good demand across
markets. So there is a play and we have
a product and we have a team which is
capable of driving this uh transition.
If you ask the beginning of the year did
we expect a uh 4 and a half% of market
share my answer would have been probably
it would have been a shade lower than
that. So there is tailwind which is also
helping us look uh better than what we
could have been. But would we have been
far would have been 4%. So it's it's
pretty much uh there and we are well
set. So we at the right place at the
right time. Uh as far as health is
concerned
uh this this I mean honestly this growth
is little extraordinary even if I looked
it from the industry um standard point
of view is it any particular channel or
or you which way not present in a
particular channel now exploring the
channel has contributed to the growth.
Oh, I tell you so that that that I can
explain you that I can sit that's what
your question was. So see the product
elevate was last last year July. Okay.
So we had started doing well in that and
that renewal base also comes and gets
added to the book. So mathematically
plus supported by the tailwind there's
an answer to that part. I mean I'm
definitely not saying that 85% of the
growth that will continue over quarters
and quarters. So mathematically speaking
the retention of a product and the
quality product is there then you get
good customers and the retention also is
very high and so there is that part
which is helping us to drive this kind
of a growth circuit.
>> Understood. But but any any new channel
which contributed like like like maybe
you were not present in one
>> of course our agency channel has opened
up significantly and we able to attract
lot more channels. So agency is uh
driving this growth but at the same time
we were on websites so we've been pretty
uh across channels uh but the
contribution percentage per se of what
was there would not have gone through a
significant change if you look at the
distribution pattern so we have seen
this growth across uh channels uh uh
some
>> okay uh Sanj the reason I'm asking is
that
>> and even and even bank for that matter
>> understood understood the reason I'm
asking this question is that is is our
payout structure to the distributor is
more skewed on N basis rather than one
by N basis and even
>> no no no no we have absolute clarity
that even if it's long-term uh what we
will do is what comes with one by as a
as a as a team for us we continue to
operate strictly on those guidelines
>> okay understood so so basically
commission payouts are also on basis to
interrupt
>> yeah yeah on that yes
>> okay understood understood thanks yeah
Madam, so it would be differentiated to
that extent that one first year would be
something and then second and third year
that obviously is the case but it is
distributed basis.
>> Understood. Understood. If if I squeeze
in one more sorry
>> sorry to interrupt sir may we request to
return to the queue for followup
questions as there are several other
participants waiting for the
>> Yeah. Yes sir.
>> Thank you so much. Our next question
comes from the line of P Jane from
Motil. Please go ahead.
>> Uh yeah hi everyone. Uh I just a couple
of questions.
>> Um just a couple of questions. Firstly
on the motor side uh Sanji we've seen a
tremendous growth in volumes and what
I've understood is there is
premiumization trends as well. Uh in
spite of that uh the uh premium growth
of the industry has uh has a decent gap
between the volume growth of the
industry as well as the uh the premium
growth what we have seen right. Uh so in
that sense what is causing that
disparity and have you seen any further
pricing aggression uh in Q3 with respect
to uh you know motor o premiums given
that uh you know it was anticipated that
the growth would be there and uh the
competition intensities increase that my
first question and second question is in
terms of retail health could you give us
some uh qualitative or some numbers as
to around uh as to what is the kind of
growth that is driving the the new
customers that are coming uh what are
they coming at you know what kind of
some assureds they are coming and also
the existing customers are they scaling
up the summer assured and maintaining
the premium levels or what's the kind of
uh trajectory that we are seeing there
>> yeah okay so on the motor side P uh
clearly if you see the growth has been
uh broadbased uh and you see small cars
these small hatchback cars being sold
far higher uh than any other car. So the
the volume growth may not necessarily
translate into a equivalent uh growth in
premium for the industry and also what
is to be noted is that this growth also
is fueled by the rationalization which
happened from 28 to 18%. Which itself
led to an impact on the yield per
vehicle going down. So it's the combined
uh thing and that is where the
realignment also had to be done by us as
a team to ensure that what we pick up
overall uh from the market uh with
respect to our own motor portfolio and
also we spoke about how the H1 uh is uh
you know seen the combined ratio getting
that's to answer the competitive
intensity that you're speaking about the
motor combined in 124 and.5 and
thereabouts had very little room to go
further down. It moved down to 128 and
if that is the kind of you know uh
development that comes in there is no
reason to believe that the competition
intensity has gone down and at the same
time you spoke about specific players
coming and coming out. Frankly speaking
our journey is very secular. you know we
we've got a decent understanding and we
back ourself in terms of what we are
picking up and what we do want to do in
this motor segment in particular uh we
are uh and we have always maintained
that we are very comfortable walking
away what is not making basic sense on
the roe level for motoriz so we do
understand we are willing to play the uh
you know game if there's an roe that
comes through even if it's on an
elevated combine but not in a in a in a
random manner where we just keep
acquiring because there's an opportunity
available. So, so that kind of a
discipline is what drives us and that's
why when the industry has moved from 124
to 128 our combine actually improved by
some a percentage and some few more
basis points in that H1 period also. So
it's it's to be taken in collaboration
while maintaining market leadership. So
uh uh further pricing aggression very
little room but we maintained that over
last couple of quarters but we are very
unfaced because our journey of how we
can slice and dice and do what makes
sense what makes sense for us. uh we
would we would back ourselves and we are
very confident that we'll be able to
deliver what is warranted for us as a
company
on uh is that pre I hope this answers
what you're seeking on motors and and
more on this
>> uh and no I think no TPI is another part
which I must add uh to say which has
made the uh yield look what it is we
have been always expecting it But it's
not come through as yet.
>> Okay. Just one thing on that motor
before you kind of answer the retail
health. Uh the hatchbacks and the
smaller cars. Uh would you say that G
given a lot of them could be the first
time buyers uh structurally and given
you have a large history of long history
of data on the same kind of vehicles
being sold and first-time buyers. Would
you say that the loss ratios or could be
higher on this segment going ahead?
>> This of course we can we can discuss in
detail but the uh the the long answer in
I'll make it short and say the cars have
also started coming with much better
safety features. The road also has
changed. So there is a lot more the
salon systems are getting digitized the
uh overlay in terms of investigating
what's gone wrong because there are
cameras everywhere across the country.
The surveillance is increased. So
there's lot more pluses, there are a lot
more minuses. I'm not saying it. Uh and
these are all the factors that we are
able to use uh to drive what we want to
drive as a team and that's the USP that
we carry, right? So we won't be too
phased by it. Uh and if we do see
segment
going out of hand, I think our ability
to take a call probably ahead of the
market is what uh is the is what
differentiates us uh as a team. I hope
again I'm able to put across what I'm
saying.
>> Yeah.
On the retail.
>> Yeah. On the retail health clearly we
have seen far more you know awareness. I
think this GST card besides of course
making it more affordable has been the
biggest marketing
you know to make the individuals and
their families to realize that health
insurance is critical and as a trend to
be very honest we do see some insured
increasing significantly. We see bulk of
our customers in the range of 7 and a
half to 10 lakhs some insured. So which
is a big positive also to just share
with all of you whenever a customer
picks up a higher sum insure their
ability to retain and be with us is much
higher because the quality of the
customer is much better. So yes it's a
big plus for us uh uh as a company.
>> Thank you so much. Wish you all the
best.
>> Thank you Praish. Thank you.
>> Thank you. Your next question comes from
the line of Ain Singh from MK Global.
Please go ahead.
>> Yeah. Hi, good evening. Uh, thanks for
the opportunity. Uh, so couple of
question. The first one is uh looking at
the impact of 1 by N in terms of a
combined ratios. Is it kind of a fair
assumption that the your multi-year
product has seen a very very strong
growth? if you can sort of provide some
color I mean within your retail health
what is the multi-year uh premium shares
so that's one second uh kind of a you
know that now we are kind of have seen 9
10 months of the year uh so for FI 27 uh
uh if I have missed I don't know uh you
can provide some kind of a uh you know
guidance on growth as well as on
combined and related partly in motor
third party should we expect uh you know
by the time your Q4 some reserve
releases given that I mean your I mean
where your reserving are sitting or kind
of a reserve releases India for 22 to 24
is still pretty minimal so is it kind of
a you know fair to assume that okay the
Q4 should see some motor TP religious
times
>> yeah so uh I think I'll go it on the
reverse way uh so motor third party I
think obviously uh Yeah. Uh I think as
an industry we all have been kind of
waiting for the price announcement. Uh
so we'll wait and see by the time we
announce uh results for the next
quarter. Hopefully we will see where we
where we land. Um so we will keep all of
you updated on that. Uh on the second
piece on uh what is it that we can
expect for the next year. I think this
is something that we had spoken even in
uh as in last quarter as in to say that
I think given the strong growth momentum
that we see kind of getting rebound back
to us. Uh what we have always maintained
is at a uh at a top line or from a
growth standpoint we have tried to see
if we can be 100 to 200 basis points at
a company level better than the industry
growth numbers. This is cutting across
all lines and uh and that is exactly
what possibly you would have seen uh
getting exhibited in quarter 3 uh for us
uh in terms of where we our growth were
viz the industry growth and even more
specifically if you would have seen even
for the month of December I think we
have had an outperformance v the overall
industry numbers so therefore that's
something that we would endeavor even as
we head into given the strong growth
momentum that one is seeing on ground
and hence to that extent that is what we
would kind of pencil in in terms of
trying to continue to gain in the
incremental market share on combined
more important than the combined I think
what we have largely spoken is to try
and see if we can continue to sustain
delivering roses in that in that range
of 18 to 20% even if you would have seen
the numbers for the 9 months it's been
roughly around 19% thereabout so hence
to that extent uh in that range of 18 to
20% so that's something that is
something is what we would look forward
again when you look at uh how we would
want to play out even for the next year
uh from an roe standpoint uh to your
first point I think it is a high
singledigit number in terms of the
proportion of long-term uh uh premiums
visally the total premium that we
underwrite um but um I think the only
thing that we would keep urging is uh I
think even as I was as I was reading the
transcript I did realize there are so
many numbers on an end and a one by n
basis across various parameters. Um so
hence to that extent if you ask us
ideally on a consist this will actually
kind of continue for even maybe for the
next three quarters because while uh
while quarter 3 of this year onwards now
we everything is on a one by n but still
there will always be a factor of the
first question that was being asked in
terms of what is the impact of acred of
last year in this quarter and so on and
so forth. So hence to that extent a far
better reflection is to keep looking at
numbers on an n basis and there if you
would have seen our combined for quarter
3 has actually been better. I think if
you look at quarter 3 of last year our
combined was roughly about 102.3%.
And this number on an N basis for
quarter 3 the current year is also so
there I just want to interject and make
this point and we had said that also
when one by came in as a company uh we
don't want to confuse at any point of
time economic value to accounting you
know we very clear so we have uh uh in
all our conversations with our team and
key personnels who are involved uh we
only discuss on end basis because that
is the true value which will get
embedded in the what comes because of
the uh accounting part is just an
outcome for us and that is the real
value uh you know value that we can add
even our budgets for that matter if you
have to share are all taken on end basis
uh uh because that's how portfolio can
be picked up in the right manner and
even cash flows can get generated
otherwise the tendency to make it
shorter and shorter would erode value
over long term sorry Yeah. Yeah.
>> Yeah. Thank you.
>> Thanks.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you. Our next question comes from
the line of Nidesh from Invest. Please
go ahead.
>> Uh thanks for the opportunity. Uh so can
you share the share of new uh in the
motor segment? What is the new and what
is uh old vehicles?
I'm trying to understand whether the
market share trends are more uh the
market share trends how they are shaping
up in both these segments are we have we
lost market share in the new side that
is reflecting into lower growth or or
it's in both both segment our market
share trends are broadly similar so so n
just for the benefit of all of you I'll
give you two numbers uh one is in terms
of mix for quarter 3 new is roughly
about 35% renewal is about 65
uh and if you see this numbers for 9
months new is about 33 and renewal book
is about 67. So in that sense relatively
for quarter 3 uh the mix is about uh 35
and 65 but more important than the mix
if you ask us I think the point that we
have been talking about given the
underlying growth momentum kind play out
with respect to new vehicle sales and
there again in the same order as in I
will give you Q3 numbers first our new
growth has been 12.4% 4%. Uh and our old
growth has been 7.7%. Translating to an
overall growth in quarter 3 in motor for
a set about 9.3. These same numbers if
you look at it on a 9-month basis the
new growth was has been 2.5%. The
renewal growth has been 6.2 translated
an overall growth of 5%. So this is
exactly the point that we have been
talking about. I think what we are
seeing is clearly an underlying strong
growth momentum coming coming in with
respect to new vehicle sales. Having
said that, that does not mean that for
us uh renewals/ retentions are not
important. I think that's equally very
very important. But what we have been
able to leverage is a combination of
both the underlying growth momentum with
respect to new vehicle sales and then of
course the continued focus on improving
retentions as well.
>> Yeah, absolutely. And uh the fact that
the 9 month average is uh when we talk
about new is 2.5 and old is 6.2 2 while
for the Q3 uh the number goes the other
way where the new is the growth has been
led by new and as in the past Gopal has
been briefing you all new has its own
set of expenses that comes but a blatio
and that consequent to that it will have
its uh impact but will have a long-term
value allocation for us as a company uh
in the past for the quarters that we
done always it was driven by old growth
and if you go back to our scripts that
we have said we have said our growth is
driven by old. So that's a big
transition. It's a big plus overall for
us and we have been able to obviously
garner more new uh in the market uh
which has helped us to get this kind of
a growth.
>> Sure. Secondly, if you can share the
loss ratio in health uh segment wise.
Yeah, I was just waiting for somebody to
ask for this. But anyway, uh so uh on uh
on uh group health uh I'll first give
the quarter three numbers and then the 9
month numbers. First I'll give you the
Q3 and 9 month numbers for last year.
Group health uh last year uh was about
97.2
and uh this number for 9 months of last
year was 97.7.
Uh the same group health numbers for
quarter 3 this year was 90.7.
and 9 month numbers is 93.2
for retail indemnity. That's the other
number that generally gets asked for. Uh
this again quarter 3 last year retail
indemnity loss ratio was 65%.
This number 9 months was 69.1
for the current year quarter 3 retail
indemnity loss ratios are 63.1
9 month loss ratio numbers are 67.3. So
again if you look at uh what we have
been telling the market is on corporate
health or group health generally we have
maintained that we are quite comfortable
running at the book with the mid90s
that's being the that's the threshold
that we have spoken about on the
corporate health and that's exactly how
it has played out on a 9-month basis and
even retail health I think the range
that we have generally spoken to the
market is to see if you're able to run
the book at a range between 65 to 70%. I
think what we are quite excited with is
the way how the growth in the book has
played out and the fact that we have
kind of largely seen maybe couple of
renewal cycles play through on the new
product that we kind of launched last
year. I think the good news is I think
the experience that you are seeing on
ground I think is kind of pretty much
holding on to the assumptions that we
had kind of pencled in when we kind of
launched this. So those are the two
numbers uh that I would kind of uh give
give away to all.
>> Sure. And lastly on the health side we
are showing very strong growth but from
a longerterm perspective how should we
uh how do we plan to manage the issue of
uh uh old lives getting subsidized by
the new lives and that lead to uh loss
ratio deteriorating over a long period
of time. uh currently we are still a
young company on the health side but as
the growth matures let's say five year
down the line how what is the strategy
to manage the overall loss ratio
so two three data points uh one is that
the penetration of retail in health in
the country overall is 5%. Okay, most of
us end up looking at group health as a
funible thing for retail cover that
awareness is building up and there's a
long play available and it's also linked
to the purchasing power if we believe
that the uh GDP growth the purchasing
power the income tax curve the GST all
are leaving this there's a significant
road available where the uh growth of
new to the insurance or new to
protection uh will keep seeing a
significant
uh uh traction and also as loss ratio
picks up which is very real and you're
absolutely spot on but at the same time
the expense and the commission of
acquisition also goes down. So there is
a counterplay that comes in and uh the
the aging book in terms of how it
evolves and develops better medical
solutioning all of that what comes into
play we can talk about that when we meet
again but there is a play available and
that's why we see a uh future as we you
know as we go about it
and there is of course and just to add
to it there's a good preventive play
that will also to become a critical
factor for each one of us in our life.
So if there was a and as a company we
would uh be very actively involved.
There's so much more available and
through I'll take care which has got
good traction in real terms. Uh we do
believe that we will play a significant
role. Right now it's all setting the
policy and admission is how we interact
but that also is progressively changing.
uh there is a good highway available uh
and it's not that sitting in our room we
don't play out and simulate as to how
this port portfolio will behave uh 2
years 3 years 5 years down the line
these are part of actual actial
modelings and we are well aware of it
>> sure sir that's it from my side thank
you
>> thank you thank you
>> thank you next question comes from the
line of sward Mukharji from BNK
securities. Please go ahead.
>> Hi sir, thank you for the opportunity.
Uh a couple of questions from my side.
First on the uh commission uh our
commission number that has increased uh
sequentially quite substantially. I just
wanted to understand that um whether
this is uh primarily due to our retail
products increasing in the mix or uh
whether you are seeing even in
commercial lines uh where you source
through maybe uh you know agents or
brokers that there has been an increase
in commission. So some color on what you
are seeing on the ground and just
because you know it's also fairly
topical that we are hearing about some
regulatory scrutiny on this side. So how
do you see the regulatory landscape
playing out? So that is the first one
and uh secondly on the group employer
employee I mean u so you said uh that uh
the loss ratio numbers uh look fairly
encouraging. So just wanted to
understand that this loss ratio outcome
is this uh more a pricing outcome or is
this that the claims environment has
become benign which is why we are seeing
this and our growth is this like uh also
a function of the base effect because
last year I think we were uh not growing
this business. So uh is that playing out
or have you become fairly more
constructive on this business than you
were earlier? Yeah, these will be my two
questions.
>> Okay, too many things into two
questions. So, yeah.
If you two questions are brilliant, we
will obviously try and address all of
them. Uh, so on the first one, Swarnab,
I think uh again this is something that
we always call out um uh and this is
what even Sanjie just at the end
responded to one of the one of the uh
questions. See our our business has to
be fundamentally looked at in the
context of a loss experience and cost of
acquisition. So therefore to that action
there are always those nuances that play
out in terms of what mix of business
that you write. Uh relatively I I think
the earlier question that was asked in
terms of the mix between new and renewal
in terms of motor and when I kind of
gave out the data points clearly you
would have seen that the proportion of
uh new was much higher particularly when
you looked at the quarter three numbers
this will be what we had seen for the
whole of 9 months. and new inherently
kind of comes with uh a high cost of
acquisition. Uh and hence to that extent
obviously and more importantly if you'd
have seen generally quarter 3 is is
typically a period of seasons. So and
more so on retail. So hence any quarter
three you go back you'll always find the
cost of acquisition to be relatively
higher than let's say what you would
have seen for other quarters. So there's
obviously an element of seasonality that
plays out when you look at the
commission uh numbers on an isolated
basis. But what we would keep saying is
to keep looking at it more on ideally
the overall combined ratio which for us
actually has dropped when you look at
the H1 numbers relative to the industry
adverse uh that has happened but and and
the second number that we keep talking
about is more on the overall expenses of
management. uh so even after considering
the impact of the uh wage code that I
spoke about of roughly about 55 crores
uh as at 9 months I think we are kind of
pretty much there uh in so far as the
limits that are laid down by the
regulatory guidelines. So hence to that
ext
I think we are very very conscious of
what we kind of source and very very
conscious of what loss experience and
the cost of acquisition that comes as a
part of it. uh to the second point on
the regulatory uh uh uh uh evolution on
this. I think honestly we we all have to
kind of wait and see how it plays out. I
think the good news is I think from a
regulatory standpoint the regulator has
been kind of instituting the right set
of guidelines for the industry. I think
a couple of years back when they kind of
introduced this overall threshold on
expense of management that was a step in
the that was a step in the very right
direction of making sure that all
companies all cost put together are well
within that threshold of 30%. And if you
look at basis public disclosures uh
roughly there are still maybe almost 21
out of 34 players are maybe possibly met
the norms there are still a lot list of
companies which are still in exance on
the expense of management. So honestly I
think what we would want to see from a
market standpoint is to make sure that
every player in the market stays within
the limit on expense of management and
then honestly we will wait for any
subsequent changes that comes from a uh
uh regulatory changes but we will be
equally kind of committed to whatever
the guidelines that the regulator lays
down. Um so that's in response to the
first point on both commission increase
and what could happen in terms of
regulatory change. to your second point
on the GHI um yes it's a combination of
both I think again this is something
that we have articulated not only in the
context of GHI in general I think what
we have stayed focused on every line is
you should see how we can remain
profitable and the very fact that the
loss numbers that I gave out is a
testimony to the fact that we have been
very very careful and selective in terms
of what risk do we want to underwrite uh
equally it's obviously a combination of
uh both the points that you made it's a
combination of let's say better price in
terms of what we are comfortable
underwriting and two we have our own
in-house claims management team. I think
they do a brilliant job in terms of
making sure that once the once a group
health account is underwritten how is it
that we can play a very very important
role in managing the overall loss
experience and at the same time giving
delight in so far as customer experience
is concerned which is again reflective
of the NPS scores that we have kind of
called out uh whether it is motor or
whether it is health uh so that's so
that's how the growth has been reflected
and again we will continue to see that
play out even as we head into quarter 4
even for the matter of fact the next
financial year.
>> Right sir and and so just on the first
question I wanted to also uh uh check on
the commercial line side. So is there
any kind of like for where you have a
intermediate source the deal has been a
claim commission inflation anything you
>> honestly commercial lines in general I
think uh has been uh if you remember I
think what we have two is commercial
lines we have generally we have our own
relationship team which acts as a direct
interface in so far as working with
corporates are concerned and hence to
that extent uh obviously relatively that
cost of sourcing tends to be very very
low but at the same time what we also
write as a part of the commercial lines
is some of theme risks uh which is which
tends to be relatively widely
distributed and there there will be an
element of cost of uh distribution but
overall the point that I made when you
look at the loss experience plus the
cost of acquisition put together on the
commercial lines book that's a very very
profitable book for us and that's the
way how we look at it again rather than
looking at one element of uh the
business that we source
>> right got it that's very helpful thank
you so much sir
>> thank you Thanks for now. Thank you.
>> Thank you.
We will take the last question from the
line of Nishin Chawat from Kota. Please
go ahead.
>> Yeah. Uh thanks for taking my question.
uh you know uh you have a very
impressive growth in retail health and
uh you know we can see an improvement in
uh you know retail uh loss ratios as
well but uh you know as as we understand
uh you know typically the lock ratios in
retail products are significantly lower
in the first uh you know 2 3 years and
then they kind of move up from there on.
So I would have kind of said that you
know this this this delta is because of
the portfolio mix. Is it something that
the new policies that are originated are
ported or they are they are originated
under under uh you know uh different
covenants or uh you know is is is the uh
you know is as a cohort level
profitability stable or improving or
deteriorating if you would give some
color on that.
So Nish again I think I'll I'll kind of
maintain the same response that I gave
in to the earlier question which is I
think the loss ratio range on retail
health as a company that we are
comfortable running at is between 65 to
70%. And so that's a number that we will
keep looking for in terms of how we are
able to stay within that. Uh to a large
part of in terms of sourcing I think
honestly what we want to do is in line
with let's say some of the uh some of
the discussions that even the government
has been doing to kind of increase uh
healthare or increase healthcare
penetration uh consequent to some of the
reforms that they have done is to kind
of improve penetration at large. So
hence I think where we are kind of
largely expanding our distribution reach
which is what we put out also as a part
of the opening transcript to say that
even on health we are do we do we are
seeing let's say an increase in tire two
tire three cities kind of contributing
and these are as we said new to
insurance uh so hence to that extent I
think so far as we are concerned uh we
would want to kind of uh continue to
expand by acquiring a lot many more new
to insurance uh customers and two and
more importantly the earlier point that
I said in terms of our ability to
continue to retain our own customers is
something that we are very much focused
on. So it'll be a combination of those
two is what will continue to drive
growth in the retail book.
>> And uh nine just to add to what Gopal is
saying see
uh we've also transformed our own
journey right and we are a multi-line
multi-product company uh for us whether
the c customer comes from the root of
motor or from health uh we are seeing it
from a comprehensive one-stop solution.
We were uh under ball in our offering
for a number of years as far as retail's
health is concerned and we know that
going in as we move along uh while we
all know that the loss ratios move
upward as we age and that's that's the
truth which I don't see would change but
at the same time you also know if we are
comprehensively dealing with this
customer the motor loss is also goes
down I mean just to share with you so
it's a very clear mix and we are very
well placed as a multi-product
multi-line line company. So what we
seeing is getting a good customer on
board and then then working with them on
a lifetime profitability. So the maths
is what plays out with is what you see
because at times you will see only
health at times you will see only motor
but what we look at it is in a far more
comprehensive offering and with a 2.9%
market which was just probably 18 months
back for us to be a four four and a half
uh where we stand as we exist quarter
three it is just helping us to build a
very well-rounded practice. I'm not
saying it was not wellrounded but health
in particular was always in a state
which was driven by GHI and under this
part we see this as a toggling part and
we see it is a very significant play in
our scheme of thing uh that's why we've
got invested and we we stay positive and
business it's always possible that one
or two lines will have a problem and
covid happened health was all over the
place but motor kind of saved the day
for us so that's the way the portfolio
gets balanced and that's Today we end up
talking about what is it that we can
generate as an ROE.
>> Yeah.
>> Got it. That's that's very
comprehensive. Just uh squeezing a last
one. Uh I'm not sure if you mentioned
this but uh uh you know in case of
health uh you know there is uh you know
the the input tax credit loss because of
GST exemption. Uh so how are you dealing
with that? Are you sharing it with the
distributors or are you absorbing it? Is
that one of the drivers for high expense
ratios? So so so clearly yes we will
have to realign our cost structure and
this is what we have done. The benefit
in totality of GST rationalization has
got passed on to the customers. Uh and
uh we had the benefit of as the volume
grows uh for us it you know in every
line of business motor or health
economies of scale will kick in. We have
a large uh health practice as a company
which is in combined from the employer
employee as well as retail health. Uh so
so definitely we'll do what is it
required to rationalize it and serve the
customer appropriately. Yes.
>> But are you sharing it with the
distributor or
>> Yeah. of course we have the industry has
shared. It's not only about us. We all
of us on the general insurance and the
retail health have uh and then the
increased volume is not impacting the
income of the distributor per se. So
there is already a counterplay which is
visible uh which can be seen in terms of
the growth. So it's not that it's one
channel which is getting impacted uh
comprehensively we are we are all able
to do better business. So yes, it's got
passed on. We have also a cost structure
because uh both part is required and
today's technology and the so much which
is going on which we have not spoken but
we can talk about it when we sit one to
one is helping us also to reduce uh cost
per transaction. uh I don't know when
you see the script which I spoke about
as to how uh we've been able to use uh
you know bots uh uh to get our digital
part of serving DIY serving
significantly up with the uh you know
operator handling it which is driven by
a lot more inconsistency and uh you know
uh time consumption which can happen. So
there is so much that is happening. So
the cost part will go down. So we will
be able to manage it on this front very
easily.
>> Perfect. That's that's that's very very
reassuring. Uh thank you very much and
all the best.
>> Thank you. Thank you and all the best.
Thank you. Okay. Great. Uh thank you so
much for joining in and uh yeah.
>> Okay.
>> Thank you very much.
>> Thank you. Thank you and have a great
2026. Thank you so much. Thank you.
Thank you on behalf of ICIC Lumbard
General Insurance Company Limited. That
concludes this conference. Thank you all
for joining us and you may now
disconnect your lines. Thank you so
much. Thank you.